Welcome to the eLearning
session, Getting
欢迎来到 elearning 课程
Started with HL7 Routing Rules.
HL7 路由规则入门。
Routing engines are
rule-based Business Processes
路由引擎是一个基于规则的 Business Process
that route messages to a
particular destination.
其将消息路由到特定的目的地。
As Business Processes,
they sit in the middle part
Business Processes 通常居于
of the configuration page.
配置页面的中间位置。
The purpose of
the routing engine
路由引擎的目的是为了
is to determine where a
message needs to be sent.
决定消息要发送至何方。
The message could be sent
to many destinations,
消息可以发送到多地，
or none at all.
或是没有目的地。////////////////////////////////////////////////不送？？？
These are most commonly used
for routing HL7 messages,
路由 HL7 消息是非常常见的，
but can be used to route
other messages, as well.
其他消息也同样可以被路由/////////////////////////////////////路由其他消息？？
An HL7 routing engine can
be added to the production
当添加一个入口连接或是 Business Service 的时候，
automatically when adding an
inbound connection or Business
一个 HL7 的路由引擎可以自动添加到 production
Service, or can be
added separately
也，可以利用配置向导
using the configuration wizards.
另外添加。
The routing engine
uses a rule set
路由引擎利用一组规则集
to decide where a
message should be sent,
来决定消息送往何处，
and whether it should be
transformed before it is sent.
以及发送前是否需要进行转换。
Each rule within a
rule set is made up
在规则集中的每条规则由
of a constraint and a
condition, and then actions.
约束，条件以及动作构成。
Constraints match on attributes
about the message coming in,
约束主要用来匹配消息的来源，
while conditions typically look
inside the message and route
而条件主要是为了查看消息的内容
based on the contents.
以及根据内容的路由。
If the conditions
and constraints
如果条件和约束
are evaluated as true, then
the action is performed.
被判定为真，那么就执行动作。
Let's look at an
existing rule set.
让我们来看一组已经存在的规则集。
If a rule is evaluated
as true and there
如果一条规则被判定为真，
is a return at the
end of that rule,
并且在规则的尾端有返回，
the routing engine
will stop processing,
那么路由引擎会在这里停止，
and will not attempt to
evaluate any more rules.
而不会继续去判定其他的规则。
If there is no return,
the routing engine
如果没有返回，那么路由引擎
attempts to match the
next rule on the list.
会试图去匹配列表中的下一条规则。
In this first example, our
first rule does have a return,
在第一个例子中，我们看到第一条规则却是有个返回，
so that means if it matches
that constraint and condition,
这意味着，如果符合其约束和条件，
it will then stop processing
and not go on to the next rule.
规则引擎会停止处理，而不会去判定下一个规则。
Here the constraint
includes the source,
这里约束包括消息源，
which is the Business
Service that sent the message
也就是发送这消息的到
to the routing engine.
路由引擎的 Business Service
In this case, we have a
dedicated routing engine
在这例子中，我们对每个 Business Service
for each Business Service.
有一个专属的路由引擎。
So this is not very important.
虽然这不是非常重要的。
We next have the doc name which
refers to the message type.
下面，我们有一个文档名可参照消息类型。//////////////////////////////???
Such as here, ORMO01,
and the schema,
如同，ORMO01 以及 schema
which is either an HL7 version
two version number, like 2.3.1,
其是 HL7 版本2 的版本号，比如 2.3.1,
or a custom variant, like
here, where we have EMR 2.3.
或是一个用户变形，如同这里的 EMR 2.3.
The condition matches
on an individual field
条件会匹配消息本身
within the message itself.
的每个单独字段。
Some of these, like
MSH6, are obvious,
这里，如 MSH6, 显而易见，
in that it refers to the sixth
field in the MSH segment.
在这里，指的是 MSH 片断的第六个字段。
But some of the more
complex expressions
但是有些表达式会比较复杂
will need more
explanation later.
我们会在后面解释。
The action part is nearly
always the Send action,
至于动作部分，基本上是发送动作
which applies any relevant
data transformation before it
就是在发送其到目的地前
is sent to the destination.
进行转换。
Notice here target
is the destination.
注意到 target 就是目的地。
So in this case, if we
match both the constraint
在这个例子里，如果我们匹配上约束
and the condition, we're going
to send it to our target called
和条件，我们将该消息发送到我们的目标
To_ProVation.
该目标称之为 To_ProVation.
Usually the destination
is a Business Operation
通常目的地为 Business Operation
or outbound connection,
but it could also
或者是出口连接，但是也可以
be another Business Process.
发送到另外一个 Business Process.
Notice we can also
implement Boolean logic
注意到，我们也可以在条件中
into our conditions,
like these ands,
进行布尔逻辑运算，比如 AND,
and we can have multiple actions
with different transformations.
并且我们可以有多个动作分别进行不同的数据转换。
Now let's create
our own rule set.
现在，让我们来创建一个我们自己的规则集。
Let's set up this business
rule through this wizard.
让我们通过向导来设置规则。
Notice here we have
an empty routing rule.
注意到，我们有一个空的路由规则。
The first thing that I want to
do is go to the General tab.
第一件事，我们先选 "General" 标签。
I then want to specify the
Production that the rule
然后我要指定哪个 Production
set will be used in.
会用这个规则集。
So later Ensemble gives
me only the valid targets
所以后面 Ensemble 会在我应用中
within my current Production.
只给我有效的目标。
So let's specify here
in our Production
所以让我们指定我们所要的 Production
Name that we want
MyHospital.HL7Engine.
名字 MyHospital.HL7Engine.
Going back to the rule set
page, we're going to add a rule.
返回到规则集页面，我们将要添加一条规则。
I'm first going to
click on rule set,
我首先点击规则集，
and then do the plus
to add a new rule.
然后选中"加号" 添加一条新规则。
Each rule has a set of
constraints and conditions.
每条规则都有一组约束和条件。
Constraints match on attributes
about the message coming in,
约束与消息来源的属性想匹配，///////////////////约束检查收到消息的属性，而CONDITION通常。。。
while conditions typically look
inside the message and route
而条件通常查看消息的内容以及
based on the contents.
基于内容的路由。
By double clicking on
the constraints box,
双击约束的选框，
we get a wizard where we
can specify attributes
我们可以看到一个指定消息属性的
about the message.
向导
Note here that source
is the Business
这里注意到，源是指
Service from which the message
router got its message.
消息路由器所接受的消息来自于哪一个
Business Service.
It can also specify the
schema, and document name here
也可以指定 schema 和文档名字，
refers to the message type.
这里指消息类型。
So for example, ADT01.
比如，ADT01.
Let's specify a
few of these here.
让我们在这里指定一些属性。/////////////////////////////??????
If we need to route
based on the contents,
如果我们需要根据内容进行路由，
we need to specify at least
schema and message type.
我们必须至少指定 schema 和消息类型。
A condition can then be
added by double clicking
然后一个条件可以在 condition 字段上
on the condition field.
通过双击添加。
From this wizard, we get a
little bit more flexibility
从这个向导，我们可以有一些自由度
in specifying what we would
like to route based on.
来指定基于什么内容来路由。
To match on an HL7 message
field, start typing HL7.{.
为了匹配一个 HL7 消息的字段，需要以 HL7.{ 开始。
As long as you have specified
schema and message structure
只要你在条件中指定了 schema 和消息结构
in the conditions,
the wizard will
向导会
give possible paths and fields.
给出可能的路径和字段。
Let's look at the
patient's identification,
让我们来看一下病人的身份信息，
patient name, given name.
病人姓名，名。
Using the pre-built functions
and operations buttons
利用头部预制的函数和运算符按钮
at the top allows you to create
more complicated conditions.
允许你创建更复杂的条件。
Lets use the f of x,
the function button,
让我们来使用一下 "fx" 的函数按钮，
to say that we want the
given name to start with j.
比如，我们要要名字的字母以 j 打头。
Once we have our rule
the way that we want it,
一但我们见好了我们想要的规则，
we can click OK.
可以点击 OK。
The last thing
that we need to add
最后所要做的事是添加
is the action, which
determines what will happen
动作，其决定当条件为真时
if the condition is true.
会发生什么。
The main thing I want to do
is send the message somewhere.
主要我想要消息发送到某地。
So I'm going to click on
When, plus sign, and send.
所以我选中 "When", 点击“+”号，然后发送。
In this case, I want to
specify the target as To_Lab,
在这例子中，我要制定目标为 To_Lab,
and click OK.
并点击 OK.
Then click OK.
然后点击 OK.
I can add a second
send action, and also
我还可以添加第二个动作，
send the message to To_Billing.
发送消息到 To_Billing.
Or I could have simply
selected both of them
或者我可以简单同时选中它们俩
here to have them
go both places.
同时发送消息到这两地。
Having them separate,
however, allows
如果将它们两个分别设置，
me to choose two
different transforms
可以允许我对两个动作有
for each send action.
不同的数据转换。
I can add more rules
to the rule set
我还可以添加更多的规则到这个规则集。
by clicking on the Add button
after clicking Rule Set.
通过点击规则集后点击 "Add" 按钮。
You most likely
will have many rules
你可能根据需求的复杂程度
based on the complexity
of your requirements.
会有许多规则。
Whenever you change
the rule set,
当你修改规则集的时候，
you must save the changes
by clicking the Save button.
你一定要通过按 “Save” 按钮保存修改的结果。
Now when we return to
the configuration page
现在，当我们返回配置页面的时候，
we need to make sure that
we change our business rule
我们一定要保证我们也修改了
name to be this new rule
that we just created.
刚产生的这条新规则的名字。
Then if we click
on the circle next
然后，如果我们点击了
From_ApplicationX_Router 边上的小圈
to From_ApplicationX_Router,
you can now
你现在可以看到
see that
From_ApplicationX_Router
From_ApplicationX_Router 同时
is sending a message both
to To_Billing and To_Lab.
发送消息到 To_Billing 和 To_Lab.
Thank you for attending
this eLearning session.
感谢您收看这个 eLearning 课程。
We hope that you learned
a little bit more
我们希望您能从中学到一些
about getting started
with HL7 routing rules.
如何使用 HL7 路由规则。